

# **GIANLUCA ALDÉ**

Address: C.so Turati 23, 10128 Torino | Tel.: +39 338 1708712

E-mail: gianlucaalde@gmail.com

#### **PROFILE**

After finishing classical lyceum, I continued my ongoing education in music and sound, already started through private classes and experience in recording studios. My Sound Design degree thesis consisted of a full adventure game in UE5, for which I worked on the original soundtrack, dialogue, sound effects, and audio integration.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# 2023 | Dialogue Audio Engineer

Successfully directed and recorded voice acting for games and animation. Worked with highly acknowledged Italian actors, such as Gianluca Iacono, Lorenzo Scattorin, Elisabetta Spinelli, Claudio Ridolfo, Silvio Pandolfi and more.

# 2022 - Today | Music Composer and Producer, DMI (Avex)

Creating eurobeat records for the Japanese market, making Eastern and Western tastes coexist in songs for a discerning audience. Constantly collaborating with singers, lyricists and management.

## 2020 - 2021 | Mix Engineer, HQS Studio; Turin

During the pandemic, I invested my time working in a recording studio, managing various genres of musicians and learning from senior colleagues.

## 2018 - 2023 | Freelance Composer, Music Producer and Audio Engineer

Gained experience offering services on online job platforms, or through advertising. Collaborated with people from different countries and learned how to handle a wide variety of client needs.

#### **EDUCATION**

# 2019 - 2023 | Sound Design at IED, Milan (108/110)

- Relevant courses: Game Audio Design (28/30), Advanced Mixing Techniques (30/30), Sound Design for Film (30/30), Recording Techniques (28/30), Law and Economics of the Performing Arts (30/30), History of Contemporary Music (30/30).
- Numerous practical experiences and multi-disciplinary collaborations with the video, animation, and computer graphics courses.

- Coordinated several student teams in audiovisual projects for marketing agencies, museums, brands, and course projects.

# 2014 - 2019 | Liceo Classico Cavour, Turin

- Learnt through the years how to handle large workloads most effectively.
- Successfully prepared younger students through teaching and tutoring.

## **SOFTWARE SKILLS**

Avid Pro Tools, Ableton Live, Logic Pro, Steinberg Nuendo, FMOD Studio, Wwise, Adobe Audition, Unreal Engine 5.

## **SOFT SKILLS**

Reliability, punctuality and priority in meeting deadlines in all situations; positivity and ability to motivate colleagues in team environments.

## **LANGUAGES**

English (C1) - Obtained First Certificate in 2014, kept studying at private institutions, stayed in England for eight months (Isle of Wight, London, Oxford, Brighton), two years co-living in Italy with native English speakers.

Japanese (N4) - Studying through private lessons, exchanges with native friends.

## **HOBBIES AND INTERESTS**

Fitness, photography, symphonic concerts, water sports, volunteering.